# Marcello Deidda

**FULLSTACK DEVELOPER** 

**CONTACTS** 

Phone: +447490216091

Email: info@marcellodeidda.com

Based in London

**PERSONAL PROFILES** 

Portfolio

LinkedIn

<u>GitHub</u>

**CodePen** 

**TECHNICAL SKILLS** 

MERN: MongoDB, Express, React, Node Python: Algorithms, Data Structs, OOP

Front-end: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

JavaScript ES6

Databases: SQLite, PostgreSQL

**CERTIFICATES** 

**Front End Development Libraries** 

April 2023 - freeCodeCamp

**Introduction to Computer Science** 

December 2022 – Harvard CS50

The Web Developer Bootcamp 2022

December 2022 – Udemy

**Javascript Algorithms and Data Structs** 

December 2021 – freeCodeCamp

**Responsive Web Design** 

November 2021 - freeCodeCamp

**LANGUAGES** 

Italian - Native Speaker

English - Full proficiency

French - Full proficiency

Japanese - Limited Proficiency

Highly skilled Fullstack Developer specialising in the MERN stack with a recent completion of a Software Engineering Bootcamp funded by the DfE. Self-motivated and passionate about continuous learning, with a strong focus on personal development. Experienced teacher and excellent communicator.

# **PORTFOLIO**

# Full Stack - Node.js / Express / MongoDB:

BookApp // [Github] (IN PROGRESS)

## Front End – HTML / CSS / Javascript / React.js:

- Work Session Pacer // [Github]
- Rating Stars // [Github]
- Finance Calculators Web // [Github]

#### **Software Development – Python / SQLite:**

Ebookstore database // [Github]

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Software Engineering Bootcamp**

#### **University of Manchester & HyperionDev**

November 2022 - February 2023

- Completed with 100% marks, ranking 2<sup>nd</sup> out of 300 students
- Developed proficiency in Python, OOP, HTML, CSS, SQLite

#### **Fullstack Developer**

**Self-employed** December 2020 – Current

- Focusing on portfolio front-end, back-end and full-stack projects.
- Continuously expanding skills through targeted courses.
- Currently developing BookApp, a reading-focused social media platform.
- Main technologies used: Node.js, Express.js, React.js, MongoDB, SQLite, Python.

#### **Violinist and music teacher**

**Self-employed** September 2015 – Current

- Performances in chamber music and orchestral settings
- Teaching violin, piano and music theory to students of 4 to 80yo
- Preparation for graded music exams with a 100% success rate

# **EDUCATION**

# **Master's Degree, Advanced Instrument Studies**

Guildhall School of Music & Drama, UK 2015 – 2016

#### Diploma di Violino (Bachelor degree equivalent)

Conservatorio di Musica di Cagliari, Italy 2011

#### **Diploma di Liceo Scientifico (A-level equivalent)**

Liceo scientifico statale "A. Pacinotti", Italy 2010

Maths, Physics, Chemistry, Biology, Literature, History, Philosophy, English, Latin, Arts